SENIOR DEVELOPER

Summary

Around Eight years of progressive experience in project planning and management, database development and administration, COTS packages (Oracle EBS), data warehouse, BI, quality assurance, ETL, SOA, business and systems analysis, and software development and design (SDLC) using technologies such as Scrum and Extreme Programming (Agile). Lead architect completing the full systems development life cycle for relational database management systems, including requirements gathering; data modeling, database design, setup and administration; graphical user interfaces; reports; utilities; systems and user documentation; systems implementation; training, and technical project leadership. Broad international project experience over multiple industries enabling strong design and problem resolution, complemented by strong written and oral communication skills.

Highlights

Operating Systems: Windows, Unix *Programming Languages: SQL, PL/SQL, JAVA, JDBC, JSP, JavaScript, HTML, XML, Shell Script *Database: Oracle 9i, Oracle 10g/11g, MySQL, SQL Server *Utility tools: Eclipse, Toad, MS Office, Erwin, MS Project, MS Visio, Jira, ODI, Tableau

Experience

01/2013 to Current

Senior Developer American Express i1/4 Cincinnati, OH

Responsible for customizing and extending applications on Oracle Projects and Order Management modules of Oracle eBusiness Suites
(EBS) Responsible for mentoring developers and analyst to create a cross functional team where same resources were able to work in
multiple stages for application development Responsible for requirements gathering and implementing new systems and solutions to meet all
business, usability and security needs Reviewed the completed code of other team members, ensuring proper logical flow and coding
standards Developed detailed specifications with clear project deliverables and timelines, ensuring timely project completion Leading the
initiative to transition the development teams from CVS to GIT for code version control Worked extensively on PL/SQL, SQL, Cursors
Triggers, Packages, Functions, Procedures and collections to develop new applications and to maintain legacy applications Created
database objects to be used in BI tools (Tableau, IBI and Discoverer) Worked extensively on SQL tuning.

06/2010 to 01/2013

Lead Oracle Database Developer Sonoco ï/4 Conyers , GA Team Lead

Responsible for database design and development of the Gallup Entrepreneur Accelerator System Team Lead, Responsible for developing
the GSPi (Gallup Student Poll report for individual students) reporting system Have worked on developing the in-house data warehouse
system called the "Survey System" Worked closely with project managers and development team members to develop detailed
specifications with clear project deliverables and timelines, ensuring timely project completion Mentored new employees and kept abreast of
emerging technologies and applications, and looked for opportunities to integrate them into operations and activities Reviewed the
completed code of other team members, ensuring proper logical flow and coding standards Worked as database architects to define,
develop, and integrate global software component features and functionality into standard software products Have worked extensively on
PL/SQL, SQL, XML, HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop new applications and to maintain legacy applications Used Erwin and Toad
for data modeling, analysis and database design for various projects Used Jira and MS project to track the various stages of software
development.

06/2007 to 07/2009

Programmer Analyst Ieee i1/4 Los Alamitos

• Managed business analysis and development efforts to ensure smooth transition; performed end to end analysis of impacted systems to ensure that development efforts were properly implemented Responsible for release of offshore projects and software deployments to production Communicated with clients to gather post-project release issues and successfully established solutions Conducted training for team members on coding principles and communication with clients Responsible for database development, including developing new applications, fixing issues in the existing applications, and tuning existing applications for better performance Developed stored procedures, functions, and packages and worked extensively on SQL, PL/SQL, and Shell scripts Responsible for application development using SOA, J2EE, JAVA, JSP, JavaScript, HTML Analyzed database processes, and optimized it for improved performance Fixed defects and performed input analysis to ensure system viability Did research on data warehouse implementation to be used in the database team.

Education

2010

 $Master\ of\ Science: Management\ Information\ Systems\ School\ of\ Business,\ The\ State\ University\ of\ New\ York\ i'/4\ City\ ,\ State\ GPA:\ 3.84/4\ Management\ Information\ Systems\ GPA:\ Sys$

2007

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science and Engineering Vellore Institute of Technology $i\frac{1}{4}$ City India GPA: 8.76/10 First Class with Distinction Computer Science and Engineering GPA: 8.76/10 First Class with Distinction

Interests

Volunteer in Blood Donation camps, 2003-2009 *Coordinated annual sporting events in VIT University in India, 2005-2007 *Coordinated "Riviera," an annual festival in VIT University, 2006-2007 *Lead Organizer, Educational Campaign for underprivileged students in Ranchi, India, 2002-2003

Additional Information

■ CERTIFIC ATIONS AND AWARDS Sun Certified Java Professional (SCID) Won Hackathor! 2016: Annual innovation IT competition

organized by WWT Received "Player of the Year" Award for exceptional performance during my first year in Gallup Received "All Star" award for successfully leading the database team for the development of Gallup Entrepreneur Accelerator System Received "Above and Beyond Award" at Cognizant Technology Solutions for above-expected technical and client expertise ACTIVITIES Volunteer in Blood Donation camps, 2003-2009 Coordinated annual sporting events in VIT University in India, 2005-2007 Coordinated "Riviera," an annual festival in VIT University, 2006-2007 Lead Organizer, Educational Campaign for underprivileged students in Ranchi, India, 2002-2003

Skills

analyst, application development, business analysis and development, BI, CSS, clients, CVS, version control, data modeling, data warehouse, Database, database design, database design and development, database development, eBusiness, Eclipse, Entrepreneur, Erwin, XML, features, functional, HTML, J2EE, JAVA, JSP, JavaScript, JDBC, Team Lead, mentoring, MS Office, MS Project, Windows, MySQL, Operating Systems, Oracle 9, Oracle Projects, Oracle, PL/SQL, Order Management, processes, coding, Programming, reporting, requirements gathering, research, Shell Script, Software development, SQL, SQL Server, Tableau, Toad, Unix, Visio